<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright (C) 2000 - 2012 Silverpeas

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
    published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
    License, or (at your option) any later version.

    As a special exception to the terms and conditions of version 3.0 of
    the GPL, you may redistribute this Program in connection with Free/Libre
    Open Source Software ("FLOSS") applications as described in Silverpeas's
    FLOSS exception.  You should have received a copy of the text describing
    the FLOSS exception, and it is also available here:
    "http://www.silverpeas.org/docs/core/legal/floss_exception.html"

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.

-->

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <author>Emmanuel Hugonnet</author>
    <title>GNU FAQ</title>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <link rel="alternate" type="application/rdf+xml" href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.rdf"> </link>
  </head>
  <body>  
    <h2><a name="cxcontent2">Silverpeas Licensing FAQ</a></h2>
    <ul>
      <li class="none">
        <p> 
          <a href="#whymove">1. Why   move to GPL? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#whichversion">2. Which version of the GPL are you using? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#doesthismakeiteasier">3. Does GPL make it easier to include Silverpeas in open source projects? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#doesgplconflict">4. Does GPL conflict with 
            Apache-licensed code.  Given that Silverpeas incorporates 
            Apache-licensed code (Lucene  and others), can Silverpeas license this 
            code as GPL? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#howwillgpl">5. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas as a licensed (paid or unpaid) user? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#ourcompany">6. Our  company has a strict policy 
            against use of GPL software. What will I  need to communicate to our 
            Legal Department on our use of Silverpeas? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/silverpeaspartner">7. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas as an Silverpeas partner? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#specificsolutions"> 8. Our  company markets specific 
            solutions built on top of Silverpeas. What are  the implications of 
            moving to GPL for our solution offerings? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#oemlicense">9. Our  company has executed an OEM 
            license for Silverpeas for use as an embedded  component of our overall 
            solution. What are the implications of a move  to GPL for us? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#currentuse"> 10. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas release? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#flossexception"> 11. What is the FLOSS exception? Does it apply to me and what does it provide for? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#model"> 12. Is there a precedent for this licensing model? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#embeds">13. What happens if a popular open source 
            project embeds and distributes Silverpeas. Is this allowable under the 
            FLOSS exception? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p> 
          <a href="#marketdev">14. How does this change in Silverpeas 
            license model fit within the overall market development of open source 
            business applications? 
          </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#policies"> 15. Will Silverpeas ever change its licensing policies again? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <a href="#addinfo"> 16. Where can I get additional information on Silverpeas  and Silverpeas licensing? </a>
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2> 
      <a title="faq1"></a> 
      <a name="whymove" id="whymove"></a>1. Why move to GPL? 
    </h2>
    <p> Silverpeas feels strongly that the future of software is open 
      source. Not  a little open source mixed with a lot of proprietary 
      source. Free and  open source software. It is open source, not hybrid 
      models that will  drive true disruption in the software industry, with 
      greater value  created for and by end-users. 
    </p>
    <p> The GNU General Public License  (“GPL”) is the ideal license to 
      drive forward this industry disruption.  The GPL ensures that no vendor –
      including Silverpeas – can control a  customer’s content. The GPL also 
      provides the maximum assurance that  the open source community and not, 
      ultimately, Silverpeas, protects  investments in our code. 
    </p>
    <p> We plan to be in business for a long  time, but wanted a license 
      that guarantees our users that Silverpeas, the  code, will always be 
      bigger and more enduring than Silverpeas, the  company. This enables our
      community to invest in the Silverpeas code with  maximum confidence 
      that the investment will grow over time, and not be  wasted. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="whichversion" title="faq2" id="whichversion"></a> 2. Which version of the GPL are you using? 
    </h2>
    <p> You may be aware that some licensors who use GPL allow their code 
      to be  licensed under the current version of GPL or “any later version.”
      This  means that the code may be accepted by a licensee under the 
      current  version (which is now version 3) and any later version released
      by the  Free Software Foundation, and the licensor may be bound by 
      either sets  of terms, depending on the choice of the licensee. Some 
      other GPL  projects, like the Linux projects, use a single version of 
      GPL. We have  decided to follow the lead of Linux on this point. 
    </p>
    <p> Until the end of 2007, our code was under GPL version 2. As in November
      2007, the final release of GPL version 3 was finalized and
      released, we took some time for reviewing the terms of the new version
      before taking any decision.  
      Our decision was taken and from that date our code is now under GPL version 3.
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2>
      <a name="doesthismakeiteasier" title="faq5" id="doesthismakeiteasier"></a> 3. Does this make it easier to include Silverpeas in open source projects? 
    </h2>
    <p> Yes, it does. Especially when you take into account our FLOSS  
      Exception. Silverpeas’s GPL + FLOSS Exception policy gives the open  
      source development community the world’s best content www with  freedom 
      to embed it in other projects, from Drupal to Jasper Reports  to…you 
      name it. In summary, the Silverpeas FLOSS Exception enables  software 
      provided under existing OSI-approved open source licenses to  
      incorporate the Silverpeas Community software without having to license 
      the entire software package under the terms of the GPL. We prefer the  
      GPL, but you may not – if you’re an open source-licensed project, we  
      give you additional choice. Please see our 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/3.floss_exception.html">FLOSS Exception</a> page for more details. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="doesgplconflict" title="faq6" id="doesgplconflict"></a> 
      4. Does GPL conflict with Apache-licensed  code. Given that Silverpeas 
      incorporates Apache-licensed code (Spring,  Lucene, and others), can 
      Silverpeas license this code as GPL? 
    </h2>
    <p> First off, this alleged incompatibility only applies to Silverpeas
      Community, which is licensed under the GPL. Those using Silverpeas  
      Enterprise get our software under a Commercial License, so they do not  
      have to worry about this at all. 
    </p>
    <p> As for Silverpeas Community  (GPLv3 license) and its incorporation 
      of Apache-licensed software, there is no incompatibility. The incompatibility
      exists only for the use both of GPLv2 code and of Apache-licensed code.
      Any GPLv3 project can include Apache-licensed code. The incompatibility raised only
      with the inclusion of GPLv3-licenced code into Apache-licenced project.
      For more information about the compatibility between the two licenses,
      please consult <a href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/GPL-compatibility.html">
      this page about the concern</a>.
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="howwillgpl" title="faq7" id="howwillgpl"></a> 5. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas as a licensed (paid or unpaid) user? 
    </h2>
    <p> Regardless of whether you’re a paid (Silverpeas Enterprise) or 
      unpaid  (Silverpeas Community) licensee, this license change will not 
      affect your  use of any software you received from us prior to February 
      20, 2007. 
    </p>
    <p> With the move to the GPL, your use will be affected depending on what kind of Silverpeas user you are: </p>
    <ul>
      <li> Silverpeas Community Users. Our re-licensing will not affect 
        your rights  in code you have accepted under the modified MPL prior to 
        February  2007. If you accepted code under that license, you can still 
        use it  under that license. However, if you download an update from us 
        of after  the February 2007 release of Silverpeas Community 2.0, the 
        update will be  covered by the GPL plus 
        <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/3.floss_exception.html">FLOSS exception</a>. 
      </li>
      <li>Silverpeas  Enterprise Users. We provide our paid Silverpeas 
        Enterprise customers  with a Commercial License. So, in short, it will 
        not affect you at all.  While we are strong advocates of open source 
        licensing, we recognize  that some amongst our customers and partners 
        may have different license  requirements. Our Commercial Licensing is 
        designed to meet these  different needs for our paid customers. Our 
        licensing change applies  only to our Silverpeas Community product. 
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="ourcompany" title="faq8" id="ourcompany"></a> 6. Our 
      company has a strict policy against use of GPL software. What will  I 
      need to communicate to our Legal Department on our use of Silverpeas? 
    </h2>
    <p> First off, we would encourage you to  try the demo of Silverpeas (see 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/form_fr.jsp">Silverpeas demo/</a>.
      It is the same code that we ship with Silverpeas  , but is more 
      rigorously tested, has full production and  development support, is 
      certified to work with leading third-party  software (databases, 
      application servers, etc.), and comes with  improved documentation, 
      immediate bug fixes, and other benefits. We  deliver it to you under a 
      Commercial License, a license that we extend  when you decide to 
      purchase an Silverpeas Enterprise Subscription. In  short, you can use 
      Silverpeas Enterprise without worrying about the GPL,  if you’re 
      concerned about it. (We prefer the GPL, but you may not, so  we give you
      choice if you’re a paid subscriber.) 
    </p>
    <p> Your company  probably instituted its policy about GPL software 
      for one of two  reasons: infringement risk and copyleft concerns. Some 
      companies want  to be sure that every bit of software in the enterprise 
      is backed by  warranties. If this is the case, you will need to use our 
      Commercial  License (Silverpeas Enterprise). But most companies are more
      concerned  about copyleft requirements -- which is the word used to 
      describe the  requirement in the GPL that redistribution must only take 
      place under  GPL terms. If that is the issue, you may or may not need 
      our Commercial  License, depending on what you want to do with our 
      software. Please see  our 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/1.licensing_gnu_affero.html">Licensing Policy page</a> for more information. 
    </p>
    <p> If, for whatever reason, you prefer to use Silverpeas Community, 
      which is  licensed under the GPL, and you don’t plan to redistribute the
      software  (with or without modifications to it), then a commonly 
      accepted  industry view is that you may use the software without 
      worrying about  needing to release your own source code (the 
      modifications to Silverpeas  Community or code you integrate with it) as
      open source software. The  copyleft requirements of the GPL are only 
      triggered upon distribution.  It is therefore commonly understood that 
      only when you distribute the  software outside your organization would 
      you would need to release your  modifications under the GPL. This is not
      legal advice from Silverpeas,  however – you should seek competent 
      legal counsel to best guide you in  this matter. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="#silverpeaspartner" title="faq9" id="#silverpeaspartner"></a> 7. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas as an Silverpeas partner? 
    </h2>
    <p> All Silverpeas partners work with and distribute Silverpeas.  Your
      rights and responsibilities are completely unchanged by this  license 
      change, which only affects Silverpeas  users. 
    </p>
    <p> If you are not an official partner and have been distributing 
      Silverpeas, you will need to abide by the rights and restrictions of the
      GPL. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="specificsolutions" title="faq10" id="specificsolutions"></a>
      8. Our company markets  specific solutions built on top of Silverpeas. 
      What are the implications  of moving to GPL for our solution offers? 
    </h2>
    <p> If you are an  official Silverpeas partner using Silverpeas 
      Enterprise, there are no  implications whatsoever to our license change.
      You will keep exercising  your Commercial License to Silverpeas 
      Enterprise, which will have terms  mutually agreed upon between 
      Silverpeas and you. 
    </p>
    <p> If you are not  an official Silverpeas partner and are combining 
      Silverpeas with open  source-licensed software consistent with our FLOSS
      Exception, you will  need to abide by the terms of our 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/3.floss_exception.html">FLOSS Exception</a> for any derivative works. 
    </p>
    <p> If you are not an official Silverpeas partner and are combining 
      Silverpeas  with proprietary software or open source-licensed software 
      that is not  consistent with our FLOSS Exception, you will need talk to 
      us about a  Commercial License or license your software under the GPL. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="oemlicense" title="faq11" id="oemlicense"></a> 9. Our 
      company has executed an OEM license for Silverpeas for use as an  
      embedded component of our overall solution. What are the implications  
      of a move to GPL for us? 
    </h2>
    <p> As an official Silverpeas partner,  you are using our software 
      under a Commercial License. This change will  not affect you in any way.
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="currentuse" title="faq12" id="currentuse"></a> 10. How will GPL affect my current use of Silverpeas ? 
    </h2>
    <p> You will need to abide by the GPL modified by our FLOSS Exception 
      if  you upgrade to a new release of Silverpeas. If you prefer to  remain
      with a previous version of the software licensed under the MPL +  
      Attribution (our 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/1.licensing_gnu_affero.html">Silverpeas Public License</a>), you will need to continue to abide by the terms of that license. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="flossexception" title="faq13" id="flossexception"></a> 11. What is the FLOSS exception? Does it apply to me and what does it provide for? 
    </h2>
    <p> Silverpeas’s 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/3.floss_exception.html">FLOSS Exception</a>
      allows specified Free/Libre and Open Source Software ("FLOSS") software
      to be able to use specified GPL-licensed Silverpeas software despite 
      the  fact that some of these other FLOSS licenses are not compatible 
      with  GPL. It is a way of allowing specified open source-licensed 
      software  projects to integrate with Silverpeas without having to change
      the  license covering their projects to GPL. 
    </p>
    <p> The Silverpeas FLOSS  Exception is only relevant to licensees 
      wishing to integrate the  Silverpeas Community software with other open 
      source-licensed projects.  Please visit our 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/1.licensing_gnu_affero.html">Licensing Policy</a> page for more details. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="model" title="faq14" id="model"></a> 12. Is there a precedent for this licensing model? 
    </h2>
    <p> Yes. MySQL and others have used FLOSS exceptions for some time. 
      They  are increasingly common in the software industry as a way to 
      provide  all the benefits of the GPL while allowing GPL-licensed 
      software to  integrate well with other open source-licensed projects, 
      which might  otherwise not be integrated due to license incompatibility.
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="embeds" title="faq15" id="embeds"></a> 13. What happens 
      if a popular open source project embeds and distributes Silverpeas. Is 
      this allowable under the FLOSS exception? 
    </h2>
    <p> If an open source project is licensed under one of the specified licenses in 
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.org/legal/3.floss_exception.html">Silverpeas’s FLOSS Exception</a>,
      then it may embed GPL-licensed Silverpeas software without requiring 
      its  software to also be licensed under the GPL. Please review the 
      Silverpeas  FLOSS Exception to ensure you are in compliance. 
    </p>
    <p> As a  potential Silverpeas customer, why would I choose to license
      Silverpeas  directly from you rather then take the embedded offering 
      from an  existing open source vendor? 
    </p>
    <p> This depends on what you are  seeking. It may well be that the 
      embedded offering, or its equivalent,  is not available from Silverpeas.
      This is one of the wonderful things  about open source: the community 
      has theoretically unlimited resources  to tailor the Silverpeas version 
      of the software to a diverse set of  needs. We help to start or continue
      “the content management  conversation” with Silverpeas – we don’t 
      expect to be the complete  conversation. 
    </p>
    <p> However, for those looking for Silverpeas  Enterprise – certified,
      rigorously tested, and supported software with  access to the vibrant 
      and growing Silverpeas Network – this is only  available from Silverpeas
      or one of our official partners. 
    </p>
    <p> The choice is yours. </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="marketdev" title="faq16" id="marketdev"></a> 14. How 
      does this change in Silverpeas’s license model fit within the overall  
      market development of open source business applications? 
    </h2>
    <p> The  software industry is dividing into two camps: monolithic, 
      proprietary  stacks (where vendors seek to provide an end-to-end 
      solution for all  computing needs) and best-of-breed, open source and 
      open standards  stacks. We are part of this latter camp, and believe 
      open source offers  customers unparalleled choice, cost savings, and 
      exceptional software.  While much of the open source software 
      applications market is still  stuck “half-way” between proprietary and 
      open source software, we  believe that we are on the front-end of a 
      growing trend toward greater  openness in software licensing, and thus 
      greater benefits for  customers. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="policies" title="faq17" id="policies"></a> 15. Will Silverpeas ever change its licensing policies again? 
    </h2>
    <p> Over time, we may need to streamline our licensing policies to 
      respond  to developer needs and to ensure the stability and commercial 
      viability  of our products. Any changes to our policy will be posted on 
      our  website. But of course, if we change our policy, and you have 
      received  a license to our code under our free licensing terms, that 
      will not  terminate the rights you have already been granted. Any 
      changes will  only apply going forward to new releases of our code. 
    </p>
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2> 
      <a name="addinfo" title="faq18" id="addinfo"></a> 16. Where can I get additional information on Silverpeas 5.0 and Silverpeas licensing? 
    </h2>
    Please visit our 
    <a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/">Products page</a> for information on Silverpeas 5.x . You can find our licensing information 
    <a href="licensing_gnu_affero.html">here</a>.
    <p align="left">
      <a href="#cxcontent2">
        <img border="0" src="../images/top.gif" alt="Haut" />
      </a>
    </p>
  </body>
</document>
