<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright (C) 2000 - 2011 Silverpeas

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
    published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
    License, or (at your option) any later version.

    As a special exception to the terms and conditions of version 3.0 of
    the GPL, you may redistribute this Program in connection with Free/Libre
    Open Source Software ("FLOSS") applications as described in Silverpeas's
    FLOSS exception.  You should have received a copy of the text describing
    the FLOSS exception, and it is also available here:
    "http://www.silverpeas.com/legal/licensing"

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.

-->
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <author>Emmanuel Hugonnet</author>
    <title>Trade Mark</title>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <link rel="alternate" type="application/rdf+xml" href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.rdf"> </link>
  </head>
  <body>  
    <h2> 1. Authorized Use of the Silverpeas Trademark</h2>
    <h3>A. Silverpeas   Logo</h3>
    <p>Silverpeas has developed a  family of "Conditional Use" Logos for 
      those who wish to show their  support for Silverpeas and its products 
      and services by displaying  such a logo in the user interface of a 
      website. The "Conditional Use"  Logos may be used without specific 
      written permission from Silverpeas. under the following conditions: 
    </p>
    <ul type="disc">
      <li>The use       must not be detrimental, i.e., harmful or damaging, 
        to the value of any of       the Silverpeas. Marks, or to Silverpeas 
        Software, its brand       integrity, reputation or goodwill, as 
        determined by Silverpeas.       in its sole discretion; 
      </li>
      <li>The       Silverpeas logo must be a "clickable" link that       leads directly to http://www.silverpeas.com/. </li>
      <li>If the       website has password-protected areas, the 
        "Conditional Use" Logo       must be placed only in areas that are not 
        password-protected 
      </li>
      <li>If used in       an application released under the GPL, LGPL, MPL,
        Silverpeas Public License       or any other Open Source Initiative 
        (http://www.opensource.org) recognized       open source license, the 
        application must be able to connect directly to       an Silverpeas 
        Software server 
      </li>
      <li>The       limited license given herein does not include the right 
        to use any       Silverpeas  logo or any other Silverpeas Logo as a 
        trademark to promote your own products or       services. For example, 
        no Silverpeas logo may be used on any       product packaging or 
        documentation, such as (without limitation) on CD-ROM       or diskette 
        labels or packaging, books or other publications. Any such use       
        must be expressly authorized by Silverpeas. in a signed,       written 
        agreement; 
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>B. General.</h3>
    <p>As a general  rule, no person or entity may use (or authorize the use
      of)  the Silverpeas logo in any manner other than as expressly 
      authorized by Silverpeas in a written agreement. Silverpeas reserves the
      right to revoke any such authorization at any time  in its sole 
      discretion, such as where use does not strictly conform to the  
      requirements of this Trademark Policy and/or Silverpeas written  
      authorization. 
    </p>
    <h3>C. Publications, Lectures, PowerPoint &amp; Other  Presentations.</h3>
    <p>Third Parties may use Silverpeas  Marks (except Silverpeas Logos) in 
      the titles of publications, such  as books or magazines, or in 
      connection with presentations, provided that the  use: (i) is 
      referential only; (ii) does not use the Silverpeas. Mark  as a 
      trademark; and (iii) complies with this Trademark Policy. Silverpeas 
      Marks must always be attributed with the proper symbol and  footnoted, 
      as explained below, on all publications and presentations that are  
      displayed to the public (sales, trade shows etc). 
    </p>
    <p>Since the Silverpeas Marks are used in these instances only to  
      describe the content of the publication or presentation and are not used
      as  trademarks to promote your own products and services, you should 
      not attempt to  establish trademark or other proprietary rights by 
      registering, or attempting  to register, the titles as trademarks, 
      service marks, corporate names or trade  names. In addition, your name 
      or mark and logo should appear in a prominent  location on the cover and
      title page of all publications and on all materials  related to the 
      presentations and should appear more prominent than the title  
      incorporating the Silverpeas Marks on all printed materials related  to 
      the publications or presentations.
    </p>
    <p>Please note that this Section 1(F) only permits referential use of a 
      Silverpeas Mark (except any Silverpeas Logo) - it does not permit  use 
      of any Silverpeas Mark as a trademark. Without the express  prior 
      written consent of Silverpeas. No Silverpeas Mark  may be used as a 
      trademark to promote any publication, lecture or other  presentation. 
    </p>
    <h2> 2. Unauthorized Use of Silverpeas Marks.</h2>
    <h3>A. General.</h3>
    <p>Unauthorized use of the Silverpeas Marks or marks that are 
      confusingly similar may constitute an infringement  of Silverpeas 
      trademark rights and is strictly prohibited.  Without the express prior 
      written consent of Silverpeas, no Silverpeas. Mark may be used in a 
      manner that implies an affiliation with or  sponsorship by Silverpeas. 
    </p>
    <h3>B. Third Party Marks.</h3>
    <p>Unless expressly authorized by Silverpeas in writing, third parties 
      generally may not use any Silverpeas. Marks as part of their company 
      names, trademarks or logos. In  other words, no person or entity may 
      combine any Silverpeas. Mark  with any third party trademark without the
      express prior written consent of Silverpeas.
    </p> 
              
                
    <p>No third party may name or rename a product or service of its own to 
      include  the word "Silverpeas" without the express prior written  
      consent of Silverpeas. Furthermore, no third party may claim any  right 
      to register, or attempt to register, a trademark in any territory if the
      trademark in question includes "Silverpeas" or is in some  other way 
      similar to any Silverpeas Mark.
    </p> 
                  
                    
    <p>In the event that Silverpeas. authorizes any of the above uses in  
      writing, the Silverpeas. Mark must be at least as large as the  
      trademark or logo of the other company. 
    </p>
    <h3>C. Internet Domain Names.</h3>
    <p>No third party may register or attempt to  register an Internet 
      domain name that includes "Silverpeas" or  any of the Silverpeas. Marks 
      or any marks that are confusingly  similar to the Silverpeas. Marks. in a
      way that is detrimental,  i.e., harmful or damaging, to the value of 
      any of the Silverpeas Marks,  or to Silverpeas., its brand integrity, 
      reputation or goodwill, as  determined by Silverpeas in its sole 
      discretion. 
    </p>
    <h3>D. Damaging Use.</h3>
    <p>The Silverpeas Marks may not be  used in a manner or with respect to 
      products that will decrease the value of  the Silverpeas Marks or 
      otherwise impair or damage Silverpeas brand integrity, reputation or 
      goodwill, including (without  limitation) use in a manner that is 
      unethical, offensive, disparaging,  defamatory, illegal or in bad taste.
    </p>
    <h2> 3. Guidelines for  Use of Silverpeas Marks.</h2>
    <h3>A. Silverpeas Mark Table.</h3>
    <p>Listed below is the current Silverpeas logo. This list will be 
      updated from time to time, at the sole  discretion of Silverpeas. In 
      addition, Silverpeas may,  at its sole discretion, modify the Silverpeas
      logo at any time.  Please refer to the Silverpeas Mark Table 
      periodically to ensure  your compliance. 
    </p>
    <h5>The Silverpeas Logo:</h5>
    <p align="left">
      <img width="328" height="202" alt="Logo SP" src="../images/logo_SP.jpg"/>
      The absence of a trademark, service mark, trade name or logo from this 
      list  does not constitute a waiver of Alfresco Software Ltd.'s trademark
      or other  intellectual property rights. 
    </p>
    <h4>B. Proper Trademark Use.</h4>
    <p>Always use Silverpeas Marks as  proper adjectives. A trademark is an 
      adjective and must not be used as a verb  or noun or in the possessive 
      or plural forms.
    </p> 
    <p>Examples of Proper Use: Silverpeas software, Silverpeas  application, 
      Silverpeas database server, Silverpeas database  management system, 
      Silverpeas code, Silverpeas source code,   Silverpeas training, 
      Silverpeas support, Silverpeas services, Silverpeas partner.
    </p>
    <p> 
      Do not alter Silverpeas Marks. When using a SilverpeasMark, never vary
      the spelling, add hyphens, make one word two, or use a  possessive or 
      plural form of the SilverpeasMark. Do not abbreviate  a Silverpeas Mark 
      to create an acronym.
    </p> 
                                          
                                            
    <p>When using a Silverpeas logo, you must never modify the design, add  
      or delete any words, or change any colors or proportions. The logo may 
      be  scaled proportionally. The logo may in its entirety be displayed in 
      black on  white background OR in white on dark - black or one-coloured -
      background. The  typesize of the trademark notice symbol may be 
      adjusted. 
    </p>
                                              
                                                
    <p>The Silverpeas Logo must be used as a stand-alone icon in  accordance 
      with this Trademark Policy, without any other third party logos  and/or 
      trademarks combined or associated with it. At least a margin  
      corresponding to the height of the "W" in the logo should be left  empty
      around the logo in the background color of the displayed logo. No  
      additional text or graphics may be placed in the margin except trademark
      symbols and the words of logo versions specifically designed by 
      Silverpeas. 
    </p>
                                                  
                                                    
    <p>Any SilverpeasLogo shall only be used in conjunction with Silverpeas 
      products and services, except as specifically agreed in writing  by 
      Silverpeas or in Section 1(A) above. 
    </p>
    <h4>C. Provide Trademark Notice Symbols.</h4>
    <p>When using any Silverpeas Mark,  you should use the TM symbol. This 
      symbol provides notice to third parties of Silverpeas rights in its 
      Marks. 
                                                      
                                                        
      Silverpeas. word marks must bear the trademark notice symbol TM in  
      the first and most prominent usage of a mark and again in the first 
      appearance  of a word mark in the text or body of copy. Notice symbols 
      must always appear  with all Silverpeas Logos. Wherever possible, 
      trademark notice  symbols should be superscripted immediately after all 
      Silverpeas.  Marks. Once proper trademark notice symbols are used, and a
      Silverpeas Mark is correctly attributed to Silverpeas.(as further  
      explained below), in permitted materials, it is not ordinarily necessary
      to  mark subsequent appearances of the trademark in the same text. 
    </p>
    <h3>D. Link to Alfresco Software Ltd. Website.</h3>
    <p>All uses of a Silverpeas Logo,  such as the "Content managed by 
      Silverpeas" Logo, in a user interface  should be linked from the logo to
      <a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/">www.silverpeas.com</a>. 
    </p>
    <h2>4. General.</h2>
    <h3>A. What is a trademark?</h3>
    <p>A trademark is a word, phrase, symbol or  design, or a combination of
      those things, that distinguishes one company's  products and services 
      from the products and services of another. Thus, although  a trademark 
      is a symbol of the source of a product or service, a trademark is  not 
      the good or service itself. For example, Silverpeas brands its content  
      management product and its other products and services using the 
      Silverpeas trademark and the other trademarks, service marks, trade 
      names, and  logos identified in Section 3(A) of this Trademark Policy 
      (collectively, the  "Silverpeas Marks" or "Marks"). 
    </p>
                                                          
                                                            
    <p>A service mark is simply a trademark that identifies the source of a 
      service. A  logo is a trademark that incorporates a design of some sort,
      such as the Silverpeas Mark that includes the "turbine" design. A 
      trademark is  not the same as a copyright or a patent. 
    </p>
    <h2>B. Trademarks and the Silverpeas Public License License.</h2>
    <p>The Silverpeas Public License is one of the  ways by which Silverpeas
      distributes Silverpeas product. TheSilverpeasPublic License permits 
      third parties to use  and redistribute the underlying software under 
      certain circumstances. Such use  and/or redistribution of 
      Silverpeassoftware products are much  welcomed by Silverpeas, but should
      be distinguished from the use of  the Silverpeas Marks. The Silverpeas 
      Public License does not provide any  license or right to use any 
      SilverpeasMark in any form or media.  Thus, although a Silverpeas Public
      License licensee may redistribute the  underlying software, a 
      Silverpeas Public License licensee may not use any Silverpeas Mark in 
      doing so without the express prior written permission of Alfresco  
      Software Ltd. Otherwise, users could be misled into thinking that 
      revisions  made by a Silverpeas Public License licensee were created or 
      endorsed by Silverpeas, or that those revisions met the quality control 
      standards of Silverpeas. 
    </p>
    <h3>C. To whom does this Trademark Policy apply?</h3>
    <p>This Trademark Policy applies to all of  Silverpeas authorized 
      partners, authorized resellers, licensees,  customers, and users of 
      Silverpeas products and services, or  products that incorporate 
      Silverpeas products or services, as  well as other third parties who 
      wish to use the Silverpeas Marks  (referred to as "Third Parties" or 
      "you"). However, except  as expressly provided in Section 1(A) below, 
      this Trademark Policy does not  constitute a license, implied or 
      otherwise, to use any Silverpeas  Mark or the Silverpeas company name. 
      Although we encourage use of  the Silverpeas "Conditional use logos" as 
      provided in  Section 1(A) above, generally, no person or entity may use 
      any Silverpeas Mark without the prior, express written permission of 
      Silverpeas.
    </p>
                                                              
                                                                
    <p>By adhering to this Trademark Policy, you help Silverpeas to  prevent 
      confusion in the marketplace and to protect and enhance the value and  
      integrity of its Marks. Silverpeas appreciates your cooperation in  this
      effort. 
    </p>
    <h2>5. Miscellaneous.</h2>
    <h3>A. Third Party Licensors.</h3>
    <p>Some Silverpeas products  include technology used under license from 
      third party licensors. You must not  use any such third party trademark 
      without express permission from the owner.  This Trademark Policy is 
      limited to Silverpeas. Marks and does not  apply to marks owned by third
      parties. 
    </p>
    <h4>B. Possible Infringements.</h4>
    <p>Please report any possible infringement  and/or misuse of any Silverpeas Mark and/or a violation of this  Trademark Policy at 
      <a href="mailto:info@silverpeas.com">info@silverpeas.com</a> 
    </p>
    <h3>6. Questions, Comments and Reports of Misuse.</h3>
    <p>Please contact Silverpeas at the email   
      <a href="mailto:info@silverpeas.com">info@silverpeas.com</a>.
    </p>
  </body>
</document>
