<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright (C) 2000 - 2012 Silverpeas

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as
    published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
    License, or (at your option) any later version.

    As a special exception to the terms and conditions of version 3.0 of
    the GPL, you may redistribute this Program in connection with Free/Libre
    Open Source Software ("FLOSS") applications as described in Silverpeas's
    FLOSS exception.  You should have received a copy of the text describing
    the FLOSS exception, and it is also available here:
    "http://www.silverpeas.org/docs/core/legal/floss_exception.html"

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU Affero General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.

-->

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Support</title>
    <author>Miguel Moquillon</author>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <title>Support</title>
  </head>
  <body>
    <p>
      The Silverpeas Collaborative Platform can be freely downloaded and deployed into your organization.
      Because it is a professional business class product, you may need some help, support or to be able
      to ask questions about how to install it in your specific environement or how to tweak it for your requirements. The Silverpeas team
      provides several ways of support, from a simple mailing-list to a business active support.
    </p>
    <section name="Mailing-lists">
      <p>
        If you don't have subscribed to any professional support and have some questions, you can join us at the
        mailing-lists below. They are hosted by Google Groups, so you will have to create an account (but it doesn't require a gmail account).
     </p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="http://groups.google.com/group/silverpeas-users">The Silverpeas user list</a> for questions about the installation and the use of Silverpeas,</li>
        <li><a href="http://groups.google.com/group/silverpeas-dev">The Silverpeas development list</a> for questions or information on the development of Silverpeas.
        This mailing-list is more dedicated to both contributors and integrators.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section name="Issue tracking">
      <p>
        We provide a web tool to track issues from our all users, customers and contributors. You can help us to improve the Silverpeas
        Collaborative Platform by submitting bug reports or by asking for new features.
      </p>
      <p>The feature asks are only treated within a business approach.</p>
      <p>Our issue tracking system is available at <a href="https://www.silverpeas.org/redmine/">Silverpeas Redmine</a>. To avoid spamming, accounts have read-only access per default. Please, send an email to support at silverpeas.com so that  we know your real person ;) and you 'll get writting rights.</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Business Support">
      <p>
      If you whish to be supported in your use of the Silverpeas Collaborative Platform or if you need some additional features or
      an adaptation of some of them to your requirements, we provides you with different levels of business supports.
      Theses offers are defined by our <a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/">commercial entity</a> which provides also some SaaS offers (<a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/fr/30/silvercloud/">SilverCloud</a>).</p>
      <p>Please consult our commercial site at <a href="http://www.silverpeas.com/">http://www.silverpeas.com/</a></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
